cloudconvert.org 2016-12-16

# CloudConvert - Privacy

Privacy is important to us! Our service can only exist if our customers trust us and our customers can be sure their data is secure. Thus, privacy has the highest priority for us. To be transparent we will explain in more detail how CloudConvert handles your data in the following. 

CloudConvert is maintained by Lunaweb Ltd, Munich (Germany). If you do not agree to our Privacy Policy and the other terms stated below, please do not use our services and let us know about your concerns. We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy and other terms stated below at any time. If changes occur, we will clearly indicate such alterations at the top of this page with the date of modification. 

### Personal Data Collected by Us

We collect the minimum amount of necessary data only. If you register, buy or subscribe for services, we need to collect more data about you. We do not collect any data from your uploaded files. 

By visiting our website and/or using our API, your IP address will be logged along with the dates and times of access. If you decide to create a CloudConvert account, we collect your eMail address and your chosen username also. Also, if you use our contact form we collect your eMail address and your name. At this point it is emphasized that we **do not** read or collect content, metadata or other data from your uploaded files. By buying a preapid package or subscribing, we need to additionally collect your full name, physical address, company name and VAT id. We do not collect your credit card data nor have access to it. This is handled by our payment providers [Stripe](https://www.stipe.com/) (for credit card payments) and [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/). Before providing any personal data to PayPal or Stripe, please make sure that you have read their privacy policies. 

### Use of Your Personal Data

We use your personal data to provide our service only. We do not make profiles or stuff like that. 

We do log your IP address to prevent abuse of our service and for broad demographic analysis. We do not link this information to any personally identifiable information. If you provide an eMail address we use it to communicate with you. If you buy a package or subscribe for our services your name, company and address is used to create the invoice. Your VAT id may be used to check if you qualify to exempt of paying VAT. 

### Handling of Your Uploaded and Converted Files

We do not look into it. You can delete your uploaded files at anytime. We do not make any backups. 

In the course of providing the service your files are transferred to and from servers of CloudConvert. We **do not** read, look into or mine any data from your files or its metadata. We do not make any copies of it. All file processing is done by machine and there is no human interaction with your files. Your files are deleted immediately and irreversible from our servers when you click the "×" symbol (on the right beside the Download button). This will happen automatically at the latest after 24 hours. 

### Sharing Your Data

We do not share your data or files. 

Your personal data and your uploaded files will not be given out our sold to anyone. No one, you did not provide the download link, will ever have access to your converted files. Please note that we may have to provide your data to the law enforcement authorities (for example, the police) at their request. 

### Keeping your Data

Files are deleted after 24h at latest. We keep your personal data until it is needed for the provision of our services. 

We will keep your personal data for as long as it is necessary to provide you with our services. If your personal data is no longer necessary, we can keep it in an identifiable form for maximum one year. Your files are deleted immediately and irreversible from our servers when use the delete button. This will happen automatically at the latest after 24 hours. 

### Modifying or Deleting Your Data

You can modify or delete your data on your own at anytime. 

Your data can be modified in the Settings menu. Also, you can delete your account there. This will delete your account and all associated data permanently. Alternatively, you can contact us and we will do it for you. 

### Security

We do a lot to make our service as secure as possible. 

We are committed to protect your personal data and your files. All transfers from and to CloudConvert are SSL encrypted. All CloudConvert servers are located in the European Union, are protected and cannot be accessed by third parties. To explain our security measurements in detail would be too extensive for this page; if you want to get more details about our security concept please feel free to contact us. 

### Cookies

We need them to provide our services. 

CloudConvert stores so-called cookies in order to be able to offer you a comprehensive range of functions and to make it easier to use our websites. Cookies are small files which are stored on your computer with the help of the internet browser. If you do not want to use cookies, you can prevent cookies from being stored on your computer using the corresponding settings on your internet browser. Please note that this may restrict the functional capability and the range of functions of our offer. 

### Third Party Widgets and Plugins

They are used on this site. Block them if you do not like them. 

This website uses third party plugins like the Google +1 button, the Facebook button, the Twitter button and Google Analytics. These plugins will also use cookies to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google/Twitter/Facebook on servers that might be outside of the European Union. To prevent this we suggest using browser plugins that block such widgets and their tracking, for example [Ghostery](https://www.ghostery.com/).
